<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>School on Swoyam&#39;s Dev Blogs</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/school/</link>
    <description>Recent content in School on Swoyam&#39;s Dev Blogs</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 19:11:04 +0545</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/school/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Proposal</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/chess_engine/literature_review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 19:11:04 +0545</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/chess_engine/literature_review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/chess_engine/logo.png&#34; alt=&#34;Logo&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chess can be traced back to nearly 1500 years with it&amp;rsquo;s earliest known predecessor called Chaturanga in India. The game of chess has long served as a testing ground for computer science, specially in the study of search algorithms, data structures and decision making under constraints. The world of chess programming has come a long way since the earliest known chess algorithm written by Alan Turing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The goal of this project is to build a chess engine entirely from scratch in Rust. The engine will be modular, with core components such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.chessprogramming.org/Bitboards&#34;&gt; Bitboards &lt;/a&gt;, move generation via &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/search?client=firefox-b-d&amp;amp;channel=entpr&amp;amp;q=magic+bitboards&#34;&gt;Magics&lt;/a&gt;, Legality checks, evaluation etc being published as a separate crates. Along side the development, the entire process will be documented in this &lt;a href=&#34;https://blogs.pswoyam.com.np&#34;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Proposal</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/chess_engine/proposal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 19:11:04 +0545</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/chess_engine/proposal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/chess_engine/logo.png&#34; alt=&#34;Logo&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chess has long served as a testing ground for computer science, specially in the study of search algorithms, data structures and decision making under constraints.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OopsMate&lt;/strong&gt; aims to be a chess engine written from scratch in Rust. The engine aims to have a baseline &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Elo_rating_system&#34;&gt;Elo Rating&lt;/a&gt; of at-least 1800. The engine itself will follow a more &amp;ldquo;classical&amp;rdquo; approach to chess engines, and the main goal of this project is to explore and benchmark different techniques used in chess programming to enhance engine performance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
